Some fears haunt you from within.
The Unfamiliar is a thriller, horror film directed by Henk Pretorius.
A British Army doctor comes back from a war, thinking that she has PTSD only to discover that there
is a more daunting malevolence at work making the life that she knew unfamiliar.
Elizabeth 'Izzy' Cormack, played by Jemima West.
Ethan Cormack, played by Christopher Dane.
Emma Cormack, played by Rebecca Hanssen.
Tommy Cormack, played by Harry McMillan-Hunt.
Auntie Mae, played by Rachel Lin.
Kaimoni, played by Tori Butler-Hart.
Dune (titled on-screen as Dune: Part One) is a 2021 American epic space opera film directed and
co-produced by Denis Villeneuve, who co-wrote the screenplay with Jon Spaihts and Eric Roth.
It is the first of a two-part adaptation of the 1965 novel by Frank Herbert,
and the first installment of Villeneuve's Dune film trilogy.
The cast includes Timothée Chalamet, Rebecca Ferguson, Oscar Isaac, Josh Brolin, Stellan Skarsgård, Dave Bautista, Stephen
McKinley Henderson, Zendaya, Chang Chen, Sharon Duncan-Brewster, Charlotte Rampling, Jason Momoa, and Javier Bardem.
Set in the distant future, the film follows Paul Atreides as his family, the noble House
Atreides, is thrust into a war for the deadly and inhospitable desert planet Arrakis.
The film is the third adaptation of Dune, following David Lynch's 1984
film and John Harrison's 2000 television miniseries.
After an unsuccessful attempt by Paramount Pictures to produce a new adaptation, Legendary Pictures acquired the
Dune film and television rights in 2016, with Villeneuve signing on as director in February 2017.
Production contracts were secured only for the first film, relying
on its success before a sequel would be produced.
Principal photography took place from March to July 2019 at locations
including Budapest, Jordan, Norway, and Abu Dhabi.
Dune was scheduled for a late 2020 release, but was
delayed due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film premiered at the 78th Venice International Film Festival on September 3, 2021, before its international release on
September 15, 2021; it was then released in United States theaters and streaming on HBO Max on October 22, 2021.
Dune grossed $411 million on a $165 million budget becoming
the tenth-highest-grossing film of 2021.
It was positively received by critics and audiences.
The film won six awards at the 94th Academy Awards and was nominated in
four other categories; it received numerous other accolades.
A sequel, Dune: Part Two, was released on March 1, 2024, with another sequel, Dune:
Part Three, based on Herbert's 1969 novel Dune Messiah, in production.
The tone is dark and intense.